Do you want to inherit Mikazuki Temple?
妳想繼承三日月寺嗎
Are you serious, Yuzuki?
妳是認真的嗎 結月
Inheriting this temple is a huge responsibility.
繼承這所寺廟可是很辛苦的哦
So, what makes you want to inherit it?
為什麼妳會想繼承呢
Because I…
因為我啊…
WORLDLY DESIRES
(世俗雜念)
(TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-)
《妙廟美少女》
Since then, I haven't talked to Akagami.
從那之後 我就再也沒跟赤神說過話了
Forget it!
算了
This has nothing to do with you, Akagami!
這件事跟赤神你沒關係吧
(Episode 12: Humans Can't Survive Alone) Is he angry?
(第十二集 人無法獨自生存) 他生氣了嗎…
He must be angry.
他肯定生氣了吧
I have to apologize to him.
我得要向他道歉才行
That's it.
我就誠心向他道歉吧
Akagami will understand me for sure.
我相信赤神他一定能理解我的
-I really appreciate it. -That's Akagami.
-真是太謝謝妳了… -是赤神的聲音
-I will pay attention. -Well, but you'll get used to it as you use it.
-我會注意的 -不過用著用著就會習慣的啦…
Huh?
咦
Why should I run away?
為什麼我要逃走啊
There are no suitable jobs on
徵才網站在年初的時候
the job site at the start of the year.
原來也沒什麼好工作啊
Don't be concerned with what I, an outsider, am doing.
那麼無關的我就自行採取行動了
It's my fault for being so childish.
都怪我當時太幼稚了
Okay, I need to talk to her today and make up with her.
好 我今天一定要和她 好好溝通 然後和她和解
Good morning, Akagami.
早安呀 赤神
G-Good morning.
早 早安
Keep up the good work today.
今天也要加油哦
Miss Yuzuki?
結月小姐
Isn't it good luck to be buried in Buddhist supplies?
居然會被佛教用品埋起來 這樣還真是吉利呢
Are you okay?
妳沒事吧
I'm fine, don't worry.
沒事沒事 你別擔心
Um, Miss Yuzuki.
那個 結月小姐
I have something…
我有些話…
Wait a moment.
等一下
Kiki?
嬉嬉姐
Yuzuki, please move these things to the warehouse.
結月 妳能幫我把這些東西 搬到倉庫去嗎
Oh. Okay.
啊 好的
Akagami, come with me for a moment.
赤神 你跟我來一下
I have something to say to you.
我有話跟你說
What do you need me for?
妳找我有什麼事
What happened between you and Yuzuki?
你和結月之間發生了什麼事嗎
Well…actually…
呃…其實
OH MY So you two had a love fight.
(唉唉唉) 什麼嘛 原來只是情侶吵架啊
No, it's just a fight.
不是 就是吵架了而已
Yeah, yeah. You guys seem to be getting along great.
好好好 你們打得還真是火熱
Initially, it was simply that we each had our own viewpoint.
一開始只是我們兩個都各持己見
I had no idea it would get so bad this time.
沒想到這次事態卻升級了…
Akagami, what is this?
赤神啊 是什麼
-Breasts… -Right.
-胸部… -沒錯
This is me, Kiki.
這是我 也就是嬉嬉
Yes, that's what I think too.
對對對 我也是這麼想的
In the eyes of different people,
尼姑 住持 師父等等
I have different identities, such as nun, abbot, master, and so on.
我在不同的人眼中有不同的身份
But you only know about my breasts.
不過你好像只認識到胸部就是了
ERR
呃啊
Fingers point to the moon, but they are not the moon itself.
以手指月 只認手指
Even when we use our fingers to indicate the moon,
即使用手指月
some people may still focus on the pointing fingers instead.
也有人會被指月的手指所束縛
Just now, I pointed at my breast on purpose
就像我剛才是為了引導你犯錯
to get you to make a mistake.
才故意指著自己的胸部一樣
Isn't that cheating?
這不是耍詐嗎
I want you to pay attention to the main idea.
我是要讓你注意看清本質啊
The finger is just a signpost.
手指只不過是路標
If you pay too much attention to that finger,
如果過於關注那根手指
you won't get the truth of the moon.
你就無法得到名為月亮的真理
What does this mean?
這是什麼意思…
How do you see
你是如何看待
Yuzuki?
結月這個人的
Miss Yuzuki
結月小姐她…
is very reliable despite her eccentricities.
雖然有些脫線的地方 但非常值得信賴
She's tenacious and always on the move…
她很能幹 態度也非常積極…
She's a lot stronger than me.
是比我強大很多的人
That's what makes you so twisted, Akagami.
這就是你在認知上的 扭曲之處啊 赤神
Kiki, we have a guest.
嬉嬉姐 有客人來了
Did the guest mention why they're here?
客人有說是來幹嘛的嗎
RELOCATE GRAVES She said she wanted to relocate the grave.
(絕緣) 她說她想要絕緣
-This is a great opportunity! -Why?
-這是個千載良機 -怎麼了
Because we can get a fee for relocating the grave!
因為我們能拿到絕緣費啊
RELOCATING GRAVES REFERS TO When parishioners relocate graves,
(所謂絕緣) 施主把墳墓遷走時
THE ACT WHERE DONORS, UPON LEAVING A TEMPLE, they typically provide the temple with relocation fees or offerings.
(就是施主在離開寺廟時) 一般會給寺廟絕緣費或禮金之類的
MOVE THEIR ANCESTORS' GRAVES OUT OF THE TEMPLE However, this means that our temple's parishioners are decreasing.
(會把祖塚遷出寺廟) 但這樣我們寺廟的施主就減少了
OR TO ANOTHER LOCATION Isn't this a concerning situation?
(或轉移到其他地方) 這不是什麼好事吧
The benefit of the present moment is paramount at the moment.
現在最重要的就是眼下的利益了
This is also the guidance of the Buddha.
這也是佛祖的指引
There's something seriously off with her mind.
這人的認知絕對已經扭曲了
Leave this matter to me.
這件事就交給我吧
I'll ask for ten times the market price.
我會讓對方吐出 高於行情幾十倍的金額的
Master, isn't that a bit too much?
師父 再怎麼說 那樣也太…
She said that she wants to relocate the ancestral grave to a temple near her home.
她們想要把祖塚 移到她們家附近的寺廟裡
After all, the area is difficult to access due to a lack of public transportation.
畢竟我們這裡交通不太方便
The guest has already left? What about the relocation fee?
客人已經回去了嗎 那絕緣費呢
Huh? I didn't receive it.
咦 我沒收呀
The relocation fee is just a token of good faith.
絕緣費只不過是心意
So we won't forcefully demand it.
所以我們不會強行索要這筆錢
Wasn't this decided when my mother was still around?
這不是從我母親那一代 就決定好的事嗎
Even though that's the principle, but…
道理是這個道理
Parishioners used to come here despite the inconvenience of transportation.
以前就算交通不便 施主們還是會願意來這裡
But that was back when my mother was still around.
但那是母親還在時的事了
Leaving the ancestral grave to current Mikazuki Temple worried the guest.
客人說她沒辦法把祖塚 安心地交給現在的三日月寺
I'm really useless.
我還真是沒用呀
I can't be like my mother.
我沒辦法變得像我母親那樣呢
I've been trying
雖然我一直
to win everyone over,
在努力讓大家認同我
but I'm still a long way from her.
但我果然還是差得遠呢
All right! I need to keep trying harder!
好 我要更加努力才行
Miss Yuzuki.
結月小姐…
It's time for you to stop practicing, Yuzuki.
結月 從今天開始 我不准妳繼續修行
You're expelled.
妳被開除了
Master, why?
師父 這到底是…
Think about the reasons yourself.
原因妳就自己去想吧
Inheriting this temple is a huge responsibility.
繼承這所寺廟可是很辛苦的哦
What makes you want to inherit it?
為什麼妳會想繼承呢
Because I…
因為我啊…
What was my answer back then?
那時我是怎麼回答的呢
Right. I don't need to practice anymore.
對了…我已經不用修行了
No way. Now is not the time to be down.
不行不行 現在不是沮喪的時候
I still have a lot to do.
我還有很多事要做呢
We'll need to keep up our efforts in the new year.
所以說 在新的一年裡 我們也要繼續努力才行
What should we do specifically?
我們具體要做什麼呢
Specifically… Um…
具體的話 呃…
Is it to commit seppuku and then write the first letter of the year in blood?
就是切腹之後 用血來寫新年初筆對吧
That's quite exotic.
真是有異國情調呢
I don't think it's that one.
那個應該是不會做的…
MIKAZUKI TEMPLE HAS 80 ZABUTONS Dry zabutons in the sun.
應該是要曬曬坐墊
IT'S MORE THAN A HUNDRED IF YOU INCLUDE THE TATAMIS Clean up the tatamis and so on.
(坐墊一百張呢) 護理一下榻榻米什麼的
Should we also clean the Buddhist supplies carefully?
(三日月寺是80畳級數) 然後細細清潔一下佛教用品吧
Aside from practicing, there are plenty of other things to do in the temple.
沒錯 寺廟除了修行以外 還有很多事要做呢
However, it appears to be a simple task.
不過聽起來還挺輕鬆的呢
It's all thanks to Akagami.
這都是多虧了赤神
He always keeps the temple clean.
他平常就把寺廟打掃得乾乾淨淨
He also regularly dries the zabutons and tatamis in the sun.
坐墊和榻榻米他也會定期晾曬
I also helped clean the Buddhist supplies.
我也有幫忙清潔佛教用品哦
But there are still many other things…
但是其他還有很多…
We can get this done quickly if we all pitch in, right?
大家一起做的話 應該很快就能搞定了吧
I see. Huh?
是嗎…咦
Where is Akagami?
赤神去哪了
He went after Kiki when she went to work.
他跟著嬉嬉姐去工作了
Why?
為什麼
Who knows, I want to know too.
誰知道 我也想知道啊
Why hasn't he read my message yet?
怎麼還沒有顯示已讀啊
I've messaged him.
我都傳訊息給他了
Is that Akagami's number?
那是赤神的聯絡方式嗎
How come you have his contact?
妳為什麼會知道呢
Why would you assume I don't have his number?
為什麼我不知道呢
I don't know either, I really want it, too.
我也不知道 好想知道啊
You're too cunning.
妳太狡猾了
STUPID GAMI Well, I have it.
(笨神) 我倒是知道
How come?
反倒是妳 妳怎麼會知道啊
Sis Tsukuyo, it's not good for you to get ahead.
月夜姐姐妳居然偷跑 這樣不好哦
Even though Akagami has won you over.
就算妳早就被赤神給攻略了…
I feel the need to correct something you said.
我才想糾正一下妳剛才的說法
LIVELY DISCUSSION Help me, Sis Yuzuki.
(七嘴八舌) 幫幫我 結月姐
Sis Yuzuki?
結月姐呢
Akagami is indeed impressive.
真不愧是赤神
Not only is his work flawless, but he is also extremely popular.
他不僅工作完美還很受歡迎
But, I'm not bad either!
但是 我也不差
It's spotless.
真的是乾乾淨淨啊…
Don't worry, Akagami.
沒問題的 赤神
I will find a solution.
我會想辦法解決的
That's right, I must do something.
沒錯 我必須做點什麼才行
Didn't Mother
我的母親…
do it all on her own?
不也是一個人做到的嗎
CONSTRUCTION WORKER, TUTOR
(道路施工 補習班導師)
HIGH PAYING JOB OFFER, ANILA
(超高收入徵才 安仁羅)
(TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-) ALL PHENOMENA ARE WITHOUT A SELF
(妙廟美少女 諸法無我)
Master, I beg you.
師父 求您了
Please allow Miss Yuzuki to resume her practice!
請您恢復結月小姐的修行許可吧
Please!
拜託您了
You ought to think about where you are saying this before saying it.
你至少看看場合吧
And don't let me repeat myself.
而且別讓我說第二遍
The current Yuzuki
現在的結月
is no longer qualified.
已經沒有資格了
Master, your credentials as an abbot are also rather peculiar.
師父您的住持資格也有一點怪怪的
So please!
所以求您了
Do you want to be expelled as well?
你也想被開除是吧
Yuzuki needs to figure this out for herself.
這個問題必須要讓結月 自己意識到才行
Other people's interference is pointless.
旁人插嘴是沒用的
Please enlighten me!
求您明示
The payment is on you.
你結一下帳吧
Master!
師父
Wow, it's raining.
哇 下雨了
I finally got in touch with you!
你終於接電話啦
Miss Tsukuyo?
月夜小姐
Sorry, I'm busy now…
抱歉 我現在有事…
Sis Yuzuki has gone missing,
先別管你有沒有事了
so it doesn't matter if you're busy or not.
結月姐不見了
She acted very peculiarly this morning.
今天早上她就怪怪的
Can you guess where she could be going?
你知不知道她會去哪
I'm very worried.
我很不安…
So Akagami,
那麼赤神
how do you see
你是如何看待
BUDDHIST SUPPLY STORE, TSUKISHITA Yuzuki?
(佛具店 月下) 結月這個人的
Miss Yuzuki is very reliable
結月小姐雖然有些脫線的地方
despite her eccentricities.
但非常值得信賴
She's tenacious and always on the move…
她很能幹 態度也非常積極…
It's freezing… What to do?
好冷…怎麼辦
I think I'm running a fever…
我好像發燒了…
I must work harder…
我必須要更加努力才行…
To get everyone to agree on me.
為了讓大家認同我
I have to learn to be independent and capable.
我必須變得能夠獨當一面才行
If I don't do this, I'll never be as successful as Mother was.
不然我就無法成為 像我母親那樣的人了…
Damn. Where else could she possibly go?
可惡 她還會去哪…
Could it be…
難道是…
Mother is beautiful, strong, and capable of anything.
我的母親既堅強又美麗 而且還無所不能
Those around her had a high regard for her…
被周圍的人深深信賴著…
Mother is a perfect person…
母親簡直就是完美的存在…
The Mikazuki Temple is going to be deserted soon.
我要將三日月寺廢寺
Get ready to leave this place.
你們做好從這裡搬出去的準備吧
Did you hear that?
知道了嗎
How did things turn out this way all of a sudden? Mother!
為什麼突然變成這樣了 母親
This is settled and final.
這是已經決定好的事情
Wait a moment, Mother!
等一下 母親
I will inherit this temple!
我會繼承這所寺廟的
Yuzuki, you are going to inherit?
結月 妳要繼承這所寺廟嗎
That is…
所以…
You can't.
妳是辦不到的
You can't save the Mikazuki Temple.
妳無法拯救三日月寺
I can't…
我辦不到嗎…
Tell me, Mother.
告訴我 母親
Is it because I'm useless?
這是因為我是個沒用的孩子嗎
Where am I falling short?
我到底欠缺了什麼呢…
I have to… reach perfection.
我必須要…變得完美…
I need to work harder…
我要再更加努力…
It's time for you to stop practicing, Yuzuki.
結月 從今天開始 我不准妳繼續修行
It's not enough… it's not enough…
還不夠…還不夠…
Miss Yuzuki, as expected, is incapable!
果然 結月小姐妳是辦不到的
I need to work even harder…
我還要再…更加努力…
You can't.
妳是辦不到的
It's not enough…
還不夠…
Do not separate our family.
不要讓我們家分崩離析啊…
Please come back, Mother.
妳快回來吧 母親…
It's freezing.
好冷啊…
She certainly wouldn't be somewhere like that.
她應該不會在那種地方的
Could it be…
難道說…
After all, Miss Yuzuki…
畢竟結月小姐
is much stronger than me.
是比我強大很多的人…
That's what makes you so twisted, Akagami.
這就是你在認知上的 扭曲之處啊 赤神
Aka…gami?
赤…神
How exactly
我究竟…
do I see Miss Yuzuki?
是怎麼看待結月小姐的啊
She manages to grin even when she's feeling down.
她即使意志消沉也要擠出笑容
Her tenacity is merely another manifestation of her insecurity.
堅強反而是她缺乏自信的另一面
The real her is so…
真正的她竟是如此…
You're so warm, Akagami.
你好溫暖哦 赤神
Can't do it. I still have a fever and can't even sit up.
不行 我還在發燒 爬不起來…
-Akagami! -Miss Yuzuki, you're awake.
-赤神 -結月小姐 妳醒啦
That's right, I need to apologize
對了 我得跟他道歉才行
I must apologize first!
我得先跟她道歉才行
Sor…
對不…
Sorry.
對不起…
I should be the one to apologize.
我才應該道歉…
I feel like we haven't talked in a long time.
總覺得 我好久沒跟赤神說話了呢
Yes.
是啊
MINERAL WATER, 10 HOURS CONTINUOUS COOLING Did you watch over me all night long?
你照顧了我…一整晚嗎
I got tired and fell asleep in the middle of the night.
我中途不小心就睡著了…
I'm sorry.
抱歉哦…
Why are you apologizing?
妳為什麼要道歉
Because…
因為…
Under that bridge… I can't believe you remember that place.
那座橋下…真虧你居然知道我在那裡
I assumed you wouldn't do
我原本也以為妳應該不會
something stupid like I did.
做出跟我一樣蠢的行動
Miss Kurage told me that you are a silly and stupid person.
不過海月小姐曾經跟我說過 結月小姐又笨又廢
Silly and stupid?
又笨又廢…
And that place holds
而且那裡對我來說
many memories for me.
是一個充滿回憶的地方
The first component of enlightenment.
最初開悟的心得其一
Humans can't survive alone.
人是無法一個人生存下去的
My father often said this.
這是我父親經常掛在嘴邊的一句話
Although he used it as an excuse to have a harem,
雖然這是他用來開後宮的藉口就是了
so I strongly disliked this phrase.
因為這是我非常忌諱的話
Then I made the decision to live alone from then on.
所以我就決定了 從此以後要一個人生活下去
But you completely overturned my thoughts.
但是妳卻將我的想法徹底推翻了
For me, under that bridge
對我來說那座橋下
is the place where my whole world turned upside down.
就是我整個世界天翻地覆的地點
So Miss Yuzuki, please let me join you from now on!
所以 結月小姐 請妳也讓我牽扯進來吧
Akagami.
赤神…
You said you wouldn't
妳當時對我說
leave me alone back then.
妳不會讓我獨自一人
But you, the one saying that,
但如今說這句話的人
are bearing the entire burden.
卻正在獨自背負著一切
Please let me
請妳讓我
be a part of your destiny, too.
也牽扯進妳的緣分之中吧
But none of this has anything to do with you, Akagami.
但是這些事…和赤神你沒有關係啊…
This time, too,
這次的事情也是…
it's all due to my lack of ability…
都是我個人能力不足…
You did nothing wrong.
赤神你並沒有錯…
You're working hard when you could be
你明明可以做些你喜歡的事情…
doing something more enjoyable.
但你每天都很辛苦…
It's my fault that you--
都是我害你這麼辛苦…
I'm doing these things entirely of my own accord.
這些事情都是我自願的
My feelings for this temple are
我對於這所寺廟的感情
as strong as yours, Miss Yuzuki.
並不輸給結月小姐妳啊
Because I am
因為我啊…
most fond of the Mikazuki Temple!
最喜歡三日月寺了
I remember now.
我想起來了…
It's for such a simple reason.
原來是這麼簡單的原因啊
Thank you, Akagami.
謝謝你 赤神…
Thank you so much.
真的很謝謝你…
We all heard it.
我們都聽到了
COLD MEDICINE How long have you been there?
(傷風藥 栓劑) 妳們什麼時候來的
We've been here since Akagami put this in your medicine.
我們在赤神給妳放入這個藥時就在了
COLD MEDICINE Did you add something to it?
(傷風藥 栓劑) 你放了進來嗎
I didn't add anything.
我沒放
Sis Yuzuki.
結月姐…
Tsukuyo.
月夜…
Idiot!
笨蛋
You really worry people!
妳害我們好擔心妳啊
Worry people!
我們真的超擔心妳的
The tickling punishment.
搔癢之刑
Perhaps the watching adult videos punishment is more to your liking?
看A片之刑是不是更合妳口味呢
Um, Sis Yuzuki.
我說 結月姐
We like Mikazuki Temple just as much as you do.
我們一樣愛著三日月寺
So don't think about ditching us.
所以妳可別想把我們甩掉啊
Everyone…
大家…
And
還有
WE'VE ALL GOT IT
(全員交換完成) 結月姐倒是快被我們甩掉了呢
The only person
赤神的號碼
who doesn't have Akagami's number is you.
只有妳一個人不知道呢
I want it too!
也讓我加入嘛
You look quite vivacious.
妳還挺有精神的嘛
Kiki.
嬉嬉姐
Um, Master!
那個 師父
Kiki, I have realized
嬉嬉姐 我終於明白
why I was expelled
為什麼我會被開除
and where I am deficient.
還有我迷失的究竟是什麼了…
I worry a lot because I'm not as competent
我因為無法做到像我母親那樣
as my mother
而感到焦慮
and therefore care too much about what other people think of me.
所以變得過分在意周圍的評價
But actually, I just want to be an abbot
但我其實只是想作為住持
to keep this temple and everyone connected.
維繫與這所寺廟和諸位的緣分啊
Please
拜託您…
allow me to continue practicing with you.
請讓我繼續跟著您修行吧
Master!
師父
Firstly, you need to get well.
妳先把身體養好吧
Let's talk about the final stage of practice afterwards.
等妳康復後再來完成 修行的最後階段吧
Thank you very much!
非常感謝您
Stop playing and get some rest.
別鬧了 給我好好躺著
Geez.
真是的
Kiki.
嬉嬉姐
-Thank you. -No need to thank me.
-謝謝您… -你沒必要向我道謝
But…
但是…
The desire for the approval of others
希望得到別人認可
is the furthest private desire
這是距離開悟
from enlightenment.
最遙遠的私慾啊
It's just that Yuzuki realized
只不過結月她自己意識到了
what attitude an abbot should have.
作為住持應該保持的態度
I
我啊
didn't do anything.
並沒有做任何事哦
Are you well enough to get up?
妳已經可以起來了嗎
My fever has subsided.
我已經退燒了
I'm giving up the part-time job.
我放棄打工了
I'll try to solicit alms
主祀神的修繕費
from the parishioners to cover the cost of the main Buddha's repair.
我會試著拜託施主們施捨一下
Will they be willing to?
大家會支持我們嗎…
I believe it will be extremely difficult as well.
我也覺得很困難
That is why, back then, I would rather sacrifice myself
所以我之前才會不惜犧牲自己
to protect Mikazuki Temple.
也要守護三日月寺
But I was mistaken about that.
但那其實是錯誤的
What results from someone's sacrifice
犧牲某人才能得來的東西
will never last.
一定不會長久的
The fifth component of enlightenment.
最初開悟的心得其五
Don't try to hide your own insufficiencies.
不要逃避自己的懦弱
I will protect Mikazuki Temple with everyone.
我會和大家一起守護三日月寺的
Yes. With everyone!
沒錯…大家一起守護
You forgot to bring this.
妳有東西忘記帶了
Oh, sorry.
啊 不好意思
You did it on purpose.
妳是故意的
No way!
怎麼可能
Akagami.
赤神哥哥…
A kiss before going out.
出門前的親親
Kurage, come back for the family meeting.
海月 放學後我們開一下家庭會議
Please don't tease me, Miss Kurage.
海月小姐 妳就不要捉弄我了
Akagami, you're an idiot.
赤神哥哥 你這個笨蛋
Idiot, idiot, idiot.
笨蛋笨蛋笨蛋
Mia, are you still not ready?
米亞 妳還沒好嗎
Coming!
我馬上就過去
S-Sorry!
對 對不起
Are you okay?
你沒事吧
This is nothing.
這點小事不算什麼
How did it suddenly get dark?
天怎麼突然黑了
It's okay, do you want to suck on my breasts?
沒事沒事 你要喝奶嗎
No need.
不用了
Mia, this is a very important parishioners tour.
米亞 這是非常重要的施主巡訪
Don't be late.
千萬不要遲到了哦
Okay.
好 好的
This is your first time helping out, good luck!
這是妳第一次去幫忙 祝妳順利
Sorry for the wait.
大家久等了
We're off now.
那我們就出發啦
Hmm, be careful on the road.
嗯 路上小心
The remaining work in the temple…
那個 寺廟裡剩下的工作…
Leave it to me.
就交給我吧
Don't worry about Mikazuki Temple.
你們就放心把三日月寺交給我吧
Yeah.
也是呢
We'll leave it to you then.
那就交給你了
Yeah
好
Only Sis Yuzuki
只有結月姐姐
did not come across anything obscene this morning.
今天早上沒遇到色色的事情
Kurage, what are you talking about?
海月妳到底在說什麼啊
Maybe there's more.
說不定還有
For example…
比如說…
See.
妳看吧
Worldly desires, begone!
世俗雜念退散
Oh my! Akagami, you idiot!
真是的 赤神你這個笨蛋